Chris Hines

+49 152 2687 4263 | chrishinesabdn@gmail.com | www.cjhin.es

SUMMARY

With over 5 years of industry experience in software design, development, testing, and deployment I am confident in producing and delivering quality products across a wide variety of markets and modern technologies.

I am a creative, practical person with an aptitude for learning and developing new skills. I particularly enjoy participating in problem-solving based roles, and thrive on applying such responsibilities in a team environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer @ Skoove - Berlin, Germany

October 2017 - January 2020

- Frontend mobile application development role (ReactJS / React Native / Redux / Objective-C).
- Heavily involved in frontend architecture design, feature implementation, and the execution of A/B tests.
- Additional responsibilities included automated testing and continuous integration system management.
- Played a key role in contributing to an agile, lean development and release cycle.

Software Developer @ IMES International - Aberdeen, Scotland

July 2014 - September 2016

- Full-stack web (ASP.NET C# / ReactJS / SQL) and application (Python / Java) development role.
- · Involved in several client-specific software projects throughout design, development, and delivery.
- Also responsible for the continuous improvement and distribution of multiple inherited, core software products.
- Additional responsibilities included database and IT infrastructure management.

EDUCATION

2010 - 2014: University of Aberdeen BA (Hons) Computing Science

Modules included:

- Application Development
- Artificial Intelligence
- Operating Systems

- Computational Intelligence
- Human-computer Interaction
- Security

In my final year honours project I produced a system capable of using natural language to describe workflow schematics to human users. The development of this project involved research, surveys, meetings with subject matter experts, and software design and development.

SKILLS

- JavaScript / React / Angular / ES6+
- Swift
- Python
- Java
- C# + Objective-C
- A/B test implementation

- SQL Server / MySQL / MongoDB
- Automated and unit test design
- Version-control systems
- Software deployment + support
- CI Systems (App Center / NeverCode)
- Agile development

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Graphic design

I am very capable at using graphical editing software such as Photoshop, GIMP, and Paint.NET. This has proven useful when designing and editing graphical assets and user interfaces for software and marketing purposes.

Music technology

I have a decent understanding of various audio and music technologies. Capable of sound editing and processing using a number of tools such as Audacity and Adobe Audition. Thorough knowledge of the various audio formats and codecs, transcoding, and spectral analysis. I enjoy using Ableton Live at a hobbyist level.

Video editing

Self-taught video editing skills and familiarity with video editing software suites such as Sony Movie Studio and Final Cut Pro. I have independently created entries for some small short film competitions.